<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>framing on Maurits van der Veen</title>
    <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/categories/framing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in framing on Maurits van der Veen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/categories/framing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Idea diffusion</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/idea-diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/idea-diffusion/</guid>
      <description>How do concepts travel?     When Black Lives Matter protests exploded in the summer of 2020, they did so on a global scale. Protests around the world invariably had a dual goal: expressing solidarity with the American BLM movement, and linking that movement&amp;rsquo;s goals to related domestic concerns. I am interested in the international spread of these kinds of political ideas: How are ideas that originate in one context mapped to another situation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framing migrants and refugees</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/refugees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/refugees/</guid>
      <description>Migrants and refugees in the public discourse     Migration is a thorny political issue almost everywhere. How are public opinion and policy choices affected by the way people think about migrants? My research looks at whether migrants are thought of differently from refugees or victims of cross-border human trafficking; how the nation of origin of migrants affects attitudes, and how competing perceptions of migrants affect both national policy and international diplomacy (especially within Europe) regarding migrants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas, Interests and Foreign Aid</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/ideasinterestsaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/ideasinterestsaid/</guid>
      <description>  Table of contents:
 The many uses of foreign aid One policy, multiple goals: framing and foreign aid Debates about aid: contents and patterns Aid frames: origins and evolution The administration of aid policy The generosity contest: determinants of aid volume The popularity contest: selecting the recipients of aid Conclusion: frames and policy  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
