<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maurits van der Veen</title>
    <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maurits van der Veen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a new website</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/blog/meta-series/01-buildsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/blog/meta-series/01-buildsite/</guid>
      <description>First steps     I have long been a fan of static websites, which are portable, compact, and do not require a lot of server overhead. Since it was time to update my woefully inadequate website, I did some research into different static website options.
 Hugo is a powerful and widely-used framework for building static websites and offers a number of attractive themes.
 Blogdown makes it easy to edit a website&amp;rsquo;s files within RStudio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Data Science for the Social Sciences and Humanities</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/datasci/01-introssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/datasci/01-introssh/</guid>
      <description>Overview     (from the introductory section of the 2021 syllabus)
Who wrote that anonymous memo? Can we track COVID infections by analyzing Google searches? Do Facebook status updates provide clues about whether U.S. regional dialects are increasingly blending together? Are wars foreshadowed by low-level conflict reported in online media? And how do conscious and unconscious biases show up in newspaper reporting?
Scholars have investigated all of these questions — and many more like them — using computational tools that identify patterns in language and text, taking as inputs the growing volumes of data that are gathered daily from our devices, computers, and smartphones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to International Relations</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/intrel/01-introir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/intrel/01-introir/</guid>
      <description>Overview     This course presents an introductory survey of international relations theory and practice. It is assumed that you have a basic exposure to world affairs, and that you keep up with current events by following the international news. The course builds on this basic background by presenting in much more detail the theories and concepts that help us analyze international relations.
One way to think about the study of international relations is to see it as examining the following question: “How do states manage their exposure to the rest of the world in such a way as to make themselves both safer and better off?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites     Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile     https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile     https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README     This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darwinian evolution in politics and society</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/other/01-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/other/01-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Overview     (from the introductory section of the 2016 syllabus)
Darwin’s theory of evolution by natural selection has had an enormous impact in the biological sciences, but also in the wider world. The reverberations of the publication of On the Origin of Species can still be felt more than 150 years later. We will examine responses to evolution by natural selection within biology, the social sciences, and among the public at large.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politics of European Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/compir/01-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/compir/01-eu/</guid>
      <description>Overview     (from the introductory section of the 2020 syllabus)
The 2016 Brexit referendum in the United Kingdom highlighted many of questions still confounding observers of European integration even after more than 60 years of development. Does disaster threaten the EU from all sides, while a glorious future awaits those who abandon ship? Or does does leaving the EU doom a country to a painful economic and political hangover?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud     Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown and page formatting</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/blog/meta-series/02-textformatting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/blog/meta-series/02-textformatting/</guid>
      <description>Basic text formatting     Basic markdown and standard html tags work in most places where text is used in the website, but not everywhere. In particular, some pieces of text do not allow internal modifications to text size. One of the few possibilities there is to use the &amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; tags to make text subscript (and therefore also smaller).
Code blocks     Code blocks are started and stopped by triple backquotes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) [1] ‘0.2.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Politics and Propaganda in Cartoons</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/other/02-cartooning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/other/02-cartooning/</guid>
      <description>Overview     (from the introductory section of the syllabus)
This seminar investigates the political and propaganda uses of cartoons and caricatures. We will look at animated propaganda as well as editorial cartoons. The power of images, animated or printed, to shape or challenge an audience&amp;rsquo;s beliefs has long been recognized. Not only is a picture worth a thousand words; the impact of cartoons may exceed that of photo or film because it is often easier in this medium to get a message across through caricature and humor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualization</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/datasci/02-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/datasci/02-visualization/</guid>
      <description>Overview     I will offer this course for the first time in the Fall of 2022. The syllabus is still under development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights and Humanitarianism</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/compir/02-hr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/compir/02-hr/</guid>
      <description>Overview     (from the introductory section of the 2019 syllabus)
What are human rights, where do they come from, and why do/should they matter? Recent events around the world underscore the importance of grappling with such questions, as they relate to a wide range of issues, from the ongoing Syrian crisis (What rights do/should refugees have? How do/should we respond to crimes against humanity committed by a government?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Relations in Theory and History</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/intrel/02-irtheory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/intrel/02-irtheory/</guid>
      <description>Overview     What is international relations, and how do we theorize about it? Most introductions to international relations concentrate on relations between states, and motivate our theoretical frameworks by appealing to universal characteristics of people, states and the way they interact.
However, both the notion that international relations is primarily about states and the idea that states have characteristics that are universal (both over time and across space) are simply, undeniably wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdoown&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;)  Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Political Economy</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/intrel/03-ipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/intrel/03-ipe/</guid>
      <description>Overview     This course analyzes the politics of international economic relations, investigating the roots and evolution of the global political economy we live with today, and focusing in particular on the rise and implications of global economic governance and globalization. We aim to answer questions such as “Why do governments adopt particular international economic policies?”, “Why do states often have trouble cooperating economically?”, “When are governments likely to promote or oppose globalization?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection  My layout is: single-series   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Relations in Disciplinary Perspective</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/intrel/04-ircrossdisc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/course/intrel/04-ircrossdisc/</guid>
      <description>Overview     Students enrolled in this course have taken classes in history, economics, sociology, and political science that introduce the basic theories, methods, and epistemologies of these disciplines. These introductory courses rarely explore the relevance of disciplinary perspectives to important questions in international relations. This course, therefore, has three main goals. It seeks to give students: (1) a better understanding of the similarities and differences in how historians, economists, sociologists, and political scientists approach the study of international relations; (2) an appreciation for the analytical benefits and limitations of integrating the four perspectives; and (3) the tools to decide how they want to focus their coursework and research going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic frames of social inequality</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/pnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/pnas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What did 9/11 mean for U.S. media coverage of Muslims and Islam?</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/bjwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/bjwa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to School with Maz Jobrani</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/blog/jobrani/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/blog/jobrani/</guid>
      <description>In his Axis of Evil Comedy tour, Maz Jobrani tells a joke that nicely encapsulates a central problem with American media coverage of Muslims. We use it as an epigraph for the first chapter of our book Covering Muslims. You can watch Maz deliver it here (it starts around 1:25).
We were thrilled to talk about the book with Jobrani and his cohost Tehran for an episode of the podcast &amp;ldquo;Back to School with Maz Jobrani&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The page 99 test</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/blog/page99/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/blog/page99/</guid>
      <description>Marshal Zeringue (@zeringuemarshal) maintains a blog in which he asks authors of books to take Ford Madox Ford&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;page 99 test&amp;rdquo; and write about the results. Covering Muslims was featured on December 22.
Here is page 99 from Covering Muslims:
Surprisingly, it is a page wholely dedicated to a figure displaying trends over time in the number of articles published mentioning Muslims in four different countries. To read our page 99 test story, click on the image below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European solidarity</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/european-solidarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/european-solidarity/</guid>
      <description>Solidarity and shared identity in Europe     The long-term viability of European integration relies on a sense that member states and publics share important connections. Whether framed in terms of a European identity, the idea of linked fates, or more prosaically economic interdependence, a feeling that states and publics are connected is essential. Where does such a feeling come from? Does it make sense to think of it as transnational solidarity?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Effect of Media Tone on Attitudes toward Muslims</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/polreligion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/polreligion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covering Muslims</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/coveringmuslims/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/coveringmuslims/</guid>
      <description>  Table of contents:
 Media coverage of Muslims: Introduction and overview The tone of Muslim coverage United States newspaper coverage of Muslims: Main patterns and group comparisons Time and tone: Major events and their impact on coverage Is the United States unique? Examining newspapers from the Anglophone North and the Global South What do newspapers talk about when they talk about Muslims? Conclusions and extensions: Islamophobia, constructing boundaries, and tone-checking the media  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idea diffusion</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/idea-diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/idea-diffusion/</guid>
      <description>How do concepts travel?     When Black Lives Matter protests exploded in the summer of 2020, they did so on a global scale. Protests around the world invariably had a dual goal: expressing solidarity with the American BLM movement, and linking that movement&amp;rsquo;s goals to related domestic concerns. I am interested in the international spread of these kinds of political ideas: How are ideas that originate in one context mapped to another situation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framing migrants and refugees</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/refugees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/refugees/</guid>
      <description>Migrants and refugees in the public discourse     Migration is a thorny political issue almost everywhere. How are public opinion and policy choices affected by the way people think about migrants? My research looks at whether migrants are thought of differently from refugees or victims of cross-border human trafficking; how the nation of origin of migrants affects attitudes, and how competing perceptions of migrants affect both national policy and international diplomacy (especially within Europe) regarding migrants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic maps using pandas</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/software/dynamicmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/software/dynamicmaps/</guid>
      <description>=&amp;gt; To do: describe mapping in more detail, and provide link to GitHub page with pandas-alive fork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MultiLexScaled</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/software/multilexscaled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/software/multilexscaled/</guid>
      <description>=&amp;gt; To do: describe MultiLexScaled in more detail, and provide link to GitHub page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic text analysis - language, emotions and judgments</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/text-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/research/text-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Software and lexica for automated text analysis     All of the ongoing research projects require an ability to analyze texts: media (both traditional and social), legislative and political debates, party platforms, etc. In particular, I am interested in improving our ability to extract information about the ways an issue is framed from texts, including the emotional and/or moral dimensions of those frames, and across multiple languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WMtranslation (word-mapped translation)</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/software/wmtranslation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/software/wmtranslation/</guid>
      <description>=&amp;gt; To do: describe WMtranslation in more detail, and provide link to GitHub page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Report on Media Portrayals</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/annual2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/annual2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good, the bad, and the ugly</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/latinx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/latinx/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atheism in US and UK Newspapers</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/atheists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/atheists/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media portrayals of Muslims</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/mediamuslimsus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/mediamuslimsus/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A campfire</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/talk/campfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/talk/campfire/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to give this talk! Stay tuned for video and slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/talk/second-seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/talk/second-seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Afro-pessimist or Africa Rising?</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/africa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/africa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/talk/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/talk/seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tachyons for Style</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/project/giraffes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/project/giraffes/</guid>
      <description>Tachyons is a design system that allows you to design gorgeous interfaces in the browser with little effort.      Because Speed     Building this static site generator theme was the first time I used an Atomic (or Functional) CSS system like Tachyons. It&amp;rsquo;s a design system that provides very small (which means fast) CSS modules that you can use in your HTML. So, rather than writing every line of CSS, you apply the style you need as you write your HTML with easy to understand shorthand class names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palmer Penguins</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/project/penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/project/penguins/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.”     — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
 Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bakeoff</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/project/bakeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/project/bakeoff/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website.      Functional Form     This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media coverage of Muslim devotion</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/devotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/devotion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fifty Years of Public (Dis)Satisfaction with European Governance</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/euprefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/euprefs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enlargement and the anticipatory deepening of European integration.</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/euenlargementdeepening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/euenlargementdeepening/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas, Interests and Foreign Aid</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/ideasinterestsaid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/publication/ideasinterestsaid/</guid>
      <description>  Table of contents:
 The many uses of foreign aid One policy, multiple goals: framing and foreign aid Debates about aid: contents and patterns Aid frames: origins and evolution The administration of aid policy The generosity contest: determinants of aid volume The popularity contest: selecting the recipients of aid Conclusion: frames and policy  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/contributors/</guid>
      <description>This website is built using the hugo-apero theme developed by Alison Hill, which in turn was built upon the blogophonic Hugo theme developed by Eric Anderson and the team at Formspree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maurits-vanderveen.netlify.app/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
